### Zhongjun (Mark) Jin

Contact

4945 Bob and Betty Beyster Building

Information

Phone: (765) 421-5014 2260 Hayward Street E-mail: markjin@umich.edu, markjin1990@gmail.com

Ann Arbor, MI 48109, USA

Website: https://markjin1990.github.io/

**OBJECTIVES** 

Applying for an industrial research scientist / applied scientist / research engineer / software engineer position starting in summer 2020.

RESEARCH Interests Build interactive data (like cleaning, integration, etc.) systems for data scientists/analysts, programmers, and non-experts using a combination of AI, HCI and PL techniques.

**EDUCATION** 

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Aug. 2014 - May 2020

Ph.D. Candidate, Computer Science and Engineering

• Advisor: Prof. Michael Cafarella and Prof. H. V. Jagadish

Purdue University, West Lafavette, IN, USA

Aug. 2011 - May 2014

B.S. in Computer Science, Mathematics

Tianjin University, Tianjin, China

Aug. 2009 - Jul. 2011

Electrical and Electronics Engineering

SELECTED Professional EXPERIENCE

#### Microsoft Research, Redmond, WA

Feb 2019 - May 2019

Research Intern (Mentored by Yeve He)

Designed and implemented a system (like the seminal FLASHFILL system) recommending string data transformation programs which standardize or normalize regular-expression-like data patterns for a given set of string data (like phone numbers, or dates) with heterogeneous data patterns. Unlike most existing systems, which synthesize programs in real time, the recommended programs in **CLX** are learned offline from a large corpus of web data and of higher quality.

#### Trifacta, San Francisco, CA

May 2017 - Sep. 2017

Software Engineering Intern (Mentored by Sean Kandel, Michael Minar, and Prof. Joe Hellerstein) Designed and implemented CLX, an interactive data cleaning system. CLX 1) automatically identifies regular-expression-like data patterns for a given set of string data with heterogeneous data patterns for non-expert users to understand, and 2) suggests pattern-based transformation programs to unify various data patterns. The work was integrated to Trifacta Cloud Wrangler as a main feature in Aug 2018 and available at https://cloud.trifacta.com/.

Qualcomm, San Diego, CA

May 2013 - Aug. 2013

Software Engineering Intern

SELECTED Research **PROJECTS** 

### FOOFAH - Programming-By-Example System for Synthesizing Data Transformation Programs.

FOOFAH performs data transformation/cleaning through programming by examples (PBE), which requires little domain knowledge from non-expert users. It efficiently discovers a sequence of data wrangling actions which guarantee to transform the raw data into the example form provided by the end user using a greedy search algorithm guided by the proposed distance metric customized for spreadsheets. The user interaction time is reduced by  $\sim 60\%$  compared to the seminal WRAN-GLER system. The system is open-sourced at https://github.com/umich-dbgroup/foofah/.

## MITHRACOVERAGE - System for Investigating Population Bias for Intersectional Fairness.

The system efficiently discovers under-represented/under-covered intersectional subgroups in a given dataset (e.g., a medical dataset may lack data records from a subgroup of "Hispanic women"), which may cause the problem of population bias. **MITHRACOVERAGE** also suggests a ranked list of subgroups in which the user could collect more data entries to remedy the above issue and ensure data fairness.

### Prism - Example-based SQL Query Synthesizer.

The system infers SQL queries using imprecise and/or incomplete user examples from the target table the user desires from a relational database. The query discovery uses a bottom-up search-based algorithm and a filter-based validation process driven by a Bayesian network which reduces the overall number of query executions on the source database by  $\sim 70\%$ .

# DEEPWRANGLER - Data Transformation Program Synthesizer Guided by a Neural Network.

Many existing Programming by Example data transformation systems require many examples from end users to find the transformation programs they actually desire. **DeepWrangler** leverages a neural network to guide the program synthesis algorithm to reduce the number of examples needed and therefore saves the user interaction time.

# SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Christopher Baik, **Zhongjun Jin**, Michael Cafarella, and H. V. Jagadish, "Constructing Expressive Relational Queries with Dual-Specification Synthesis", in *CIDR* 2020.
- 2. **Zhongjun Jin**, Michael Cafarella, H. V. Jagadish, Sean Kandel, Michael Minar, and Joseph M. Hellerstein, "CLX: Towards verifiable PBE data transformation", in *EDBT* 2019.
- 3. **Zhongjun Jin**, Christopher Baik, Michael Cafarella, H. V. Jagadish, and Yuze Lou, "Demonstration of a Schema Mapping System Using Multiresolution Constraints", in *CIDR* 2019.
- 4. Abolfazl Asudeh, **Zhongjun Jin**, and H. V. Jagadish, "Assessing and Remedying Coverage for a Given Dataset", in *ICDE* 2019.
- 5. **Zhongjun Jin**, Michael R Anderson, Michael Cafarella, and H. V. Jagadish, "Foofah: Data Transformation By Example", in *SIGMOD* 2017.

### Honors and Awards

- 1st Prize in "Systems, Software Engineering and Computer Science" session in *Michigan Engineering Graduate Symposium 2017 (EGS 2017) Graduate Research Contest*, 2017.
- Selected as "Best of Demos" at SIGMOD 2017.
- Sigmod Travel Award, 2017.
- University of Michigan Departmental PhD Fellowship, 2014.
- Outstanding Undergraduate Research Endeavor Award, Purdue Computer Science Dept, 2014
- Purdue Computer Science Neel Memorial Scholarship, 2013
- Purdue Computer Science Departmental Scholarship, 2012

### INVITED TALKS

 $\bullet$  "Intelligent Self-service Data Preparation: Problems and Solutions", 11/15/2018, Llamasoft Inc., USA.

#### SERVICE

• External Reviewer: SoCC'19